dfs.co.uk 2012-11-24

# dfs | making everyday more comfortable

DFS takes the privacy of its customers’ data very seriously. Please read the following policy to understand how we will treat your personal data after it has been collected by us through your use of our Website and through the Telephone Shopping Service. 

## When do we collect data?

We can collect data on you from a variety of different sources these include: 

  * When you request a call back from one of our personal shopping advisors. 
  * When you speak to a personal shopping advisor. 
  * Via implicit data capture measures such as studying which pages you read the most and the use of cookies. 
  * When you sign up to the “my favourites” service.

## What do we do with your personal information?

When you give us any personal data as indicated above, we may need to collect information about you to provide you with the services you expect then and in the future, and to communicate with you. This information may include, but is not limited to, details such as your name, your address, email address and your phone number. 

We may also collect, and our third party providers may collect, information about where you are on the internet (e.g. the URL you came from, IP address, domain types like .co.uk and.com) your browser type, the country and telephone area code where your computer is located, the pages of our website that were viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms that you entered on our website (“User Information”). We may collect this information even if you do not register with us. 

You should be aware that this site is being monitored and may capture information about your visit that will help us improve the quality of our service. 

We confirm that any Personal Information which you provide to us (or which is available on public registers) and any User Information from which we can identify you, is held in accordance with the registration we have with the Data Commissioner’s Office. We use your information only for the following purposes: 

  * Processing your orders; 
  * For statistical or survey purposes to improve this Website and its services to you; 
  * To serve website content and advertisements to you; 
  * To administer this website; 
  * Unless you object, to notify you of products or special offers that may be of interest to you. 

You agree that you do not object to us contacting you for any of the above purposes whether by telephone, e-mail or in writing and you confirm that you do not and will not consider any of the above as being a breach of any of your rights under the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003. 

You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your Personal Information and/or User Information, we may feel obliged to do so. 

Unless we have your express consent we will only disclose personal data to third parties if this is required for the purpose of completing your enquiry. This is of course subject to the proviso that we may disclose your data to certain permitted third parties, such as members of our own group, our own professional advisers who are bound by confidentiality codes, and when we are legally obliged to disclose your data. 

DFS retains and uses your personal information to provide you with the best experience by providing you with a personalised service, and for internal administration and analysis. 

To provide you with the very best service, we may monitor or record our calls for training purposes. 

We do not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes. 

## Cookies

As part of our high security standards, when you enter this website we will use cookies. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. These cookies do not store any personal details relating to you. We also use JavaScript to speed up your online shopping experience. If you disable either cookies or JavaScript, it will seriously restrict your use of this website. 

## Data

If you have completed a credit agreement, DFS Trading Limited will pass your information to the credit provider noted on your document. The credit provider may ask credit reference agencies about you. They will keep a record of each enquiry to help them decide whether to grant credit. If they decide not to do so, DFS Trading Limited may pass the same information to alternative providers who may carry out their own credit searches. The names of the other providers are available on request. If you purchase the 5 Year Anti-Stain cover your information will also be held on computer or other files by Pinnacle Insurance and any agents or associated company for the purposes of administering this policy, including carrying out customer surveys, claims handling and fraud prevention. In the UK we operate and are registered in accordance with applicable data protection legislation. 

## Consent

By disclosing your personal information to us using this Website or over the telephone, you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information by DFS in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy. 

## Security

We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose on-line. You accept the inherent security risks of providing information and dealing on-line over the internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless this is due to our negligence or willful default.
